<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outreaches on The Vera-Licona Lab</title>
    <link>/outreach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outreaches on The Vera-Licona Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Genomic Data Skills Training for Professors (CT)</title>
      <link>/outreach/bigdataprofs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/bigdataprofs/</guid>
      <description>Project Title Modeling and Simulation in Systems Biology
Program Location Center for Quantitative Medicine, University of Connecticut Health Center, 263 Farmington Ave, Farmington, CT 06032
Program Background This program at The Jackson Laboratory for Genomic Medicine is funded by the NIH Big Data to Knowledge (BD2K) Initiative. The purpose of the course is to offer training to professors from small colleges, regional universities, HBCU and INBRE institutions in big data-computational biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSF Summer Research Experience for Undergraduates</title>
      <link>/outreach/reu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/reu/</guid>
      <description>Project Title Modeling and Simulation in Systems Biology
Program Location Center for Quantitative Medicine, University of Connecticut Health Center, 263 Farmington Ave, Farmington, CT 06032
Program Background A 10-week, in-residence, intensive summer research program, focused on modeling and simulation in systems biology, for U.S. citizen or permanent resident undergraduate students from around the United States and Puerto Rico. It will provide participants with a broad view of available career opportunities for mathematical scientists in academia, industry, and government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UConn Health Junior  &amp; Senior Doctors Academy Program</title>
      <link>/outreach/uchc_hsprogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/uchc_hsprogram/</guid>
      <description>Outreach activities with 11th and 12th grade students through the Department of Health Career Opportunity Programs at UConn Health. This is a program for 11th and 12th graders comprised of classes (e.g. Math and Science) and enrichment courses that include independent projects in STEM, enrichment trips and guidance in career objectives and goals. We will deliver seminars for the participant students, designed to expose them to the many possibilities on STEM career paths and how they contribute to society, including life sciences and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UConn Health Summer Research Fellowship Program</title>
      <link>/outreach/uchc.undergrad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/uchc.undergrad/</guid>
      <description>This is a yearly summer research experiences for undergraduates run by the Department of Health Career Opportunity Programs at UConn Health through the Aetna Health Professions Partnership Initiative (Aetna HPPI). We will merge the REU activities with those of the Department of Health Career Opportunity’s Summer Research Fellowship Program, a 10-week research enrichment experience for college juniors, seniors and recent graduates. Every summer, we will receive one student from this program and incorporate her/him into the research and career development activities we coordinate through the REU program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>