<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Vera-Licona Lab on The Vera-Licona Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Vera-Licona Lab on The Vera-Licona Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>OCSANA_V2</title>
      <link>/tools/ocsana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/ocsana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction
Targeted therapies interfering specifically one protein activity, are promising strategies in the treatment of diseases like cancer. However, accumulated empirical experience has shown that targeting multiple proteins in signaling networks involved in the disease, is often necessary. Thus one important problem in biomedical research is the design and prioritization of optimal combinations of interventions to repress a pathological behavior, while minimizing side-effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCSANA (Optimal Combinations of Interventions from Network Analysis) is a software designed to identify and prioritize optimal and minimal, combinations of interventions to disrupt the paths between source nodes and target nodes. When specified by the user, OCSANA seeks to additionally minimize the side-effects that a combination of interventions can cause on specified off-target nodes. With the crucial ability to cope with very large networks, OCSANA includes exact and selective enumeration approaches for the combinatorial interventions’ problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REACT</title>
      <link>/tools/react/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/react/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt;The inference of gene regulatory networks (GRNs) from system-level experimental observations is at the heart of systems biology due to its centrality in gaining insight into the complex regulatory mechanisms in cellular systems. This includes the inference of both the network topology and dynamic mathematical models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This software contains a novel network inference algorithm within the algebraic framework of Boolean polynomial dynamical system (BPDS). The algorithm considers time series data, including that of perturbation experiments such as knock-out mutants and RNAi experiments. To infer the network topology and dynamic models, it allows for the incorporation of prior biological knowledge while being robust to significant levels of noise in the data used for inference. It uses an evolutionary algorithm for local optimization with an encoding of the mathematical models as BPDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REACT is wrapped in a Docker container based on the AlgoRun framework. You can easily run REACT from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source code can be downloaded from our GitHub repository in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tutorial:&lt;/strong&gt; This tutorial contains a description of the terms, parameters and features in REACT’s software. It can be downloaded here: Tutorial.pdf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also include a folder with a sample of all the input files: SampleInputFiles.zip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Team:&lt;/strong&gt;
Paola Vera-Licona
Abdul Jarrah
Luis David Garcia-Puente
John McGee
Reinhard Laubenbacher&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Information:&lt;/strong&gt; Paola Vera-Licona&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDIE</title>
      <link>/tools/tedie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/tedie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Full description of TEDIE with
1) documentation
2) downloadable data sample
3) Link to preprint in BioArXiv (and eventually to paper)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Time-Series Data Discretization on Inference Methods</title>
      <link>/publication/discretization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/discretization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paola Vera-Licona</title>
      <link>/team/vera-licona/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/vera-licona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;jhb&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing Signal Transduction in signaling networks modeled as Boolean Networks, Petri Nets and hypergraphs</title>
      <link>/publication/signalingflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/signalingflow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lauren Marazzi</title>
      <link>/team/marazzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/marazzi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;jhb&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromatin interaction networks revealed unique connectivity patterns of broad H3K4me3 domains and super enhancers in 3D chromatin</title>
      <link>/publication/quin2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/quin2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD169&#43; marginal zone macrophages orchestrate innate immune responses to bacterial infection</title>
      <link>/publication/spleenmacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/spleenmacs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Minimal Hitting Set Generation Problem: Algorithms and Computation</title>
      <link>/publication/mhss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mhss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlgoRun: a Docker-based packaging system for platform-agnostic implemented algorithms</title>
      <link>/publication/algorun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/algorun/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QuIN: A Web Server for Querying and Visualizing Chromatin Interaction Networks</title>
      <link>/publication/quin1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/quin1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CQM Research Experience for Undergraduates (REU)</title>
      <link>/outreach/reu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/reu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Title&lt;/strong&gt;: Modeling and Simulation in Systems Biology
Program Location: University of Connecticut Health Center, 263 Farmington Ave, Farmington, CT 06032
&lt;strong&gt;Program Background&lt;/strong&gt;: A 10-week, in-residence, intensive summer research program, focused on modeling and simulation in systems biology, for U.S. citizen or permanent resident undergraduate students from around the United States and Puerto Rico.  It will provide participants with a broad view of available career opportunities for mathematical scientists in academia, industry, and government.  Participants will have the opportunity to expand their professional network of peers and mentors.
For more information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://cqm.uchc.edu/biomath/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://cqm.uchc.edu/biomath/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of Novel Network Inference Methods</title>
      <link>/project/reverseengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/reverseengineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of our research work is related to the development and application of algorithms related to the different undertakings for the reverse-engineering of dynamical systems, with an emphasis on discrete dynamical systems. These undertakings include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Data discretization,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) Static Network and Dynamical Model’s Inference,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) Validation and Benchmarking of Reverse-engineering Algorithms,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(4) Model Analysis and Simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UConn Health Junior  &amp; Senior Doctors Academy Program</title>
      <link>/outreach/uchc_hsprogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/uchc_hsprogram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Outreach activities with 11th and 12th grade students through the Department of Health Career Opportunity Programs at UConn Health.  This is a program for 11th and 12th graders comprised of classes (e.g. Math and Science) and enrichment courses that include independent projects in STEM, enrichment trips and guidance in career objectives and goals. We will deliver seminars for the participant students, designed to expose them to the many possibilities on STEM career paths and how they contribute to society, including life sciences and medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
