<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Control on The Vera-Licona Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/control/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Control on The Vera-Licona Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer Reversion: Computational Systems Biology Approaches</title>
      <link>/project/cancerreversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cancerreversion/</guid>
      <description>Cancer reversion is the biological process by which tumorigenic cells lose all, or a significant part of, their malignant phenotype. The objective of this project is to develop and apply novel computational systems biology tools to identify molecular drivers of cancer reversion, their mechanisms of action and their clinical application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Model Control to Reverse Cisplatin Resistance in Triple Negative Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>/project/tnbc_math/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tnbc_math/</guid>
      <description>Triple-negative breast cancers (TNBCs) are a unique group of clinically aggressive breast cancers for which surgery and chemotherapy are the only available therapeutic modalities. Dr. Ed Liu and his lab, identified a genomic configuration called the tandem duplicator phenotype (TDP) that defines a major subgroup of TNBC. TDP tumors are initially highly sensitive to cisplatin. Despite their initial responsiveness, they develop resistance to cisplatin therapy. The challenge addressed by the proposed project is to test and validate an analysis pipeline to identify therapeutic interventions to reverse cisplatin resistance in TNBC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure-based Control to Reverse Cisplatin Resistance in Triple Negative Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>/project/tnbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tnbc/</guid>
      <description>Triple-negative breast cancers (TNBCs) are a unique group of clinically aggressive breast cancers for which surgery and chemotherapy are the only available therapeutic modalities. Dr. Ed Liu and his lab, identified a genomic configuration called the tandem duplicator phenotype (TDP) that defines a major subgroup of TNBC. TDP tumors are initially highly sensitive to cisplatin. Despite their initial responsiveness, they develop resistance to cisplatin therapy. The challenge addressed by the proposed project is to test and validate an analysis pipeline to identify therapeutic interventions to reverse cisplatin resistance in TNBC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of Novel Network Inference Methods</title>
      <link>/project/reverseengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/reverseengineering/</guid>
      <description>Much of our research work is related to the development and application of algorithms related to the different undertakings for the reverse-engineering of dynamical systems, with an emphasis on discrete dynamical systems. These undertakings include:
(1) Data discretization,
(2) Static Network and Dynamical Model’s Inference,
(3) Validation and Benchmarking of Reverse-engineering Algorithms,
(4) Model Analysis, Control and Simulation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure-Based Control of Dynamical Systems</title>
      <link>/project/structurecontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/structurecontrol/</guid>
      <description>Network control has been originally developed as part of systems and control theory. While the methods developed in this area have been applied successfully to many engineered and natural systems, several factors have limited its application to large complex biological systems such as cellular signaling networks. These include the limited scalability of the methods for large networks with thousands of components, incomplete information to build dynamical models with hundreds of variables, and the linearity assumption for the underlying dynamics by which bi-stability, that characterizes signaling networks, might be affected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>