<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graduate on The Vera-Licona Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/graduate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graduate on The Vera-Licona Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/graduate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MEDS 6455: Introduction to Systems Biology</title>
      <link>/outreach/sysbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/sysbio/</guid>
      <description>Course Number and Title MEDS 6455: Introduction to Systems Biology
Course Description The course will guide students into a biology world as seen by engineers, physicists, mathematicians and computer scientists. The goal is to provide the necessary background to read modeling papers, choose Systems Biology resources that will help in biological projects, and be able to select a modeling technique appropriate for a given biological project.
Vera-Licona&amp;rsquo;s Research Group Involvement Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEDS6498: Topics in Bioinformatics and Computational  Biology</title>
      <link>/outreach/topicsbioinf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outreach/topicsbioinf/</guid>
      <description>Course Number and Title MEDS6498; Topics in Bioinformatics and Computational Biology.
Course Description The focus of the course is on the study of cutting edge computational problems related to the study and treatment of diseases, and discussion of relevant technologies. The course provides a practical introduction to current bioinformatics and computational biology topics of interest in cancer biology, immunology, microbiome and statistical genetics research, along with genomics, systems biology, single cell technologies, and cloud-based computing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>