<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boolean-networks on The Vera-Licona Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/boolean-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Boolean-networks on The Vera-Licona Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/boolean-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DiscreeTest</title>
      <link>/tools/discreetest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/discreetest/</guid>
      <description>Description DiscreeTest, is a two-step evaluation metric for ranking discretization methods for time-series data. The underlying assumption of DiscreeTest is that an optimal discretization method should preserve the dynamic patterns observed in the original data across all variables.
Link to the paper: Y Li, T Jann, P Vera-Licona. (2019). Benchmarking time-series data discretization on inference methods. Bioinformatics 35 (17), 3102 - 3109.
Github repository with source code: https://github.com/VeraLiconaResearchGroup/Benchmarking_TSDiscretizations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REACT</title>
      <link>/tools/react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/react/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The inference of gene regulatory networks (GRNs) from system-level experimental observations is at the heart of systems biology due to its centrality in gaining insight into the complex regulatory mechanisms in cellular systems. This includes the inference of both the network topology and dynamic mathematical models. This software contains a novel network inference algorithm within the algebraic framework of Boolean polynomial dynamical system (BPDS). The algorithm considers time series data, including that of perturbation experiments such as knock-out mutants and RNAi experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>