<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structure-based-control on The Vera-Licona Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/structure-based-control/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structure-based-control on The Vera-Licona Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/structure-based-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OCSANA_V2</title>
      <link>/tools/ocsana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/ocsana/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Targeted therapies interfering specifically one protein activity, are promising strategies in the treatment of diseases like cancer. However, accumulated empirical experience has shown that targeting multiple proteins in signaling networks involved in the disease, is often necessary. Thus one important problem in biomedical research is the design and prioritization of optimal combinations of interventions to repress a pathological behavior, while minimizing side-effects.
OCSANA (Optimal Combinations of Interventions from Network Analysis) is a software designed to identify and prioritize optimal and minimal, combinations of interventions to disrupt the paths between source nodes and target nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure-Based Control of Dynamical Systems</title>
      <link>/project/structurecontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/structurecontrol/</guid>
      <description>Network control has been originally developed as part of systems and control theory. While the methods developed in this area have been applied successfully to many engineered and natural systems, several factors have limited its application to large complex biological systems such as cellular signaling networks. These include the limited scalability of the methods for large networks with thousands of components, incomplete information to build dynamical models with hundreds of variables, and the linearity assumption for the underlying dynamics by which bi-stability, that characterizes signaling networks, might be affected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>